# Jay Coughlan

:: 250-508-7413 :: Jay.A.K.Coughlan@Gmail.com :: JayAKCoughlan.com::

**Jay Coughlan** is a programmer living in the Vancouver area. He has graduated from BCIT and VFS with diplomas in Computer Systems Technology and Video Game Design respectively. His years in customer service have taught him how to work well as a team and on his own, to take responsibility for his tasks, and has helped expand his problem-solving abilities. Jay has worked as a programmer and Jr. Systems Administrator on multiple projects using various programming languages and working with teams of varied specialties. He is quick to learn new tools and wants to build on his education while contributing to a great team.

#### Technical Skills:

- ➤ Programming Languages C#, Java, Javascript, C++, C, HTML + CSS
- System Administration Tools Windows Powershell, VMware, Jenkins, Windows Server 2008/12, Linux
- Technical Tools Unity3D, Visual Studio, Android Studio, DirectX 9, Office360, GitHub, GitFlow, Windows OS, Linux OS (Ubuntu, Kali), Mac OS

# Work Experience:

Sept. 2017 - Current

Shaw Cable – eCare TSR; Vancouver, BC

- > Strong communication with different team members
- Troubleshooted technical issues with customers
- ➤ Dealt with many different devices and configurations
- Quickly learned tools and skills for better troubleshooting and resolution steps
- Kept track of issues and incidents using Case Management ticketing system

# Jan. 2016 - Sept. 2016

Absolute Software – Junior Systems Administrator; Vancouver, BC

- Developed and updated dashboard application
- ➤ Worked with servers and server applications
- > Developed *Powershell* scripts to manage passwords on systems
- Compared various products for potential use

# Projects:

# *Cave Flier – BCIT Project:*

- Part of a four-programmer team
- > First person virtual reality flight game with randomly generated obstacles and consumables
- ➤ Used *C#* and *Unity3D*
- > Three-week production cycle
- ➤ Used GoogleVR

### Password Updater Script – Absolute Software Project:

- > Designed as an internal tool for Absolute Software's hosting operations team
- ➤ Used Powershell, the Powershell markup language, and PasswordState API's
- ➤ Used *C#* and *Unity3D*
- > Three-month project in between other responsibilities
- Created script to automate and manage checking password ages and generating new passwords
- > Connected to DRAC and Windows Server OS's to checked against repository, and changed passwords

# Dashboard Script:

- Designed as an internal tool for Absolute Software's hosting operations team
- ➤ Used C#, Selenium, and AutoIt3
- Loaded a Google Chrome browser with multiple dashboard tabs, logged in to every dashboard, and cycled through
- > Updates pushed to GitLab were pulled using Jenkins on remote computer, and updated

# Education:

# Jan. 2015 – Jun. 2017

B.C.I.T.

- ➤ Completed Term 1 4; Earned a diploma in *Computer Systems Technology*
- Completed BCIT's co-op program at Absolute Software (Jan 2016-Sept. 2016)
- > Digital Processing Option- Learned about image manipulation, compression, and audio programming.
- Created a five-week game 'Skippy's Gold' for Android
- Created three-week VR game 'Cave Flier' for Google Cardboard on Android

#### Oct. 2011 - Oct. 2012

Vancouver Film School

- Diploma in Game Design
- Lead programmer on my team's three-month final project, 'Moon Child'
- ➤ Learned many facets of the game design process and documentation
- ➤ Learned how to take on many roles and responsibilities

# Hobbies and Interests:

Dragons, video games with friends, writing and critiquing with my writing group, fantasy novels about dragons, Pokémon, Doctor Who, dungeons and dragons, and not being killed by dragons in dungeons and dragons.

# References:

#### Ignacio Vallejoh:

- > Teammate on Moon Child; Game play Assistant Producer at EA Games, Vancouver
- Cell Number: (604) 442-5587
- Work Email: ignacio.ava@gmail.com

#### Geoff Bucar:

- ➤ Hosting Operations Manager at *Absolute Software*, *Vancouver*,
- Work Number: (604) 630-5379
- ➤ Work Email: Gbucar@Absolute.com